babybunting.com.au 2016-11-12

# Privacy Policy | Baby Bunting

## Our privacy commitment

Baby Bunting is committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information. We manage your personal information in an open and transparent way.

Baby Bunting will only use your personal information when it is necessary for us to deliver you a service or perform other necessary business functions and activities.

Baby Bunting will not use or disclose your personal information for purposes unrelated to the services we provide, unless we first obtain your consent.

Where we can, we will allow you to deal with us anonymously or by using a pseudonym. However, in some circumstances, this may not be possible, and Baby Bunting may need to collect personal information from you to provide you with a delivery or other service. In some cases, if you do not provide the required personal information we will not be able to provide you with a service.

* * *

### Our privacy obligations

Baby Bunting is bound by privacy laws, which regulate how we may collect, use, disclose and store personal information.  These laws also specify how individuals may access and correct personal information held about them.

“Personal Information” means information or an opinion about an identified individual (or an individual who is reasonably identifiable), whether true or not, or recorded in a material form or not. For example, these types of information could include your name, contact details, age and other information.

In this policy ‘we’, ‘us’, ‘our’ and ‘Baby Bunting’ refers to Baby Bunting Pty Ltd (ACN 128 546 154).

If you have any questions regarding Baby Bunting’s Privacy Policy, please contact us via email to [enquiries@babybunting.com.au](mailto:enquiries@babybunting.com.au).  If you would like Baby Bunting to send you a copy of this policy, please contact us and we will do so. By visiting our websites and/or providing your personal information to us, you consent to the terms and conditions in this Privacy Policy, unless you tell us to the contrary by contacting our [Privacy Contact Officer](http://www.babybunting.com.au/contacts/).

This privacy policy is effective from March 2014. From time to time, our privacy policies and procedures will be reviewed and, if appropriate, updated.  If any changes are made to this policy these will be posted on our websites.

* * *

### How and why does Baby Bunting collect and hold your personal information?

Baby Bunting will only collect personal information about you by lawful and fair means, and not in an unreasonably intrusive manner.

It is Baby Bunting’s usual practice to collect personal information about you (and possibly about your family) directly from you when you:

  * complete an online form on one of our websites; 
  * complete a hard copy form;
  * join our VIP card program;
  * contact our repair or lay-by centre; 
  * enter one of our competitions; or
  * contact us by telephone, via mail, e-mail or online.

We may collect personal information about you from a third party or a publicly available source, but only if you have consented to such collection, or would reasonably expect us to collect your personal information in this way. 

Baby Bunting only collects personal information for purposes that are directly related to our business activities, and only when it is necessary for or directly related to such purposes. We also collect personal information related to employment services, human resource management, and other corporate service functions.

If we receive information about you from a third party and it is not information we need in respect of our business activities, we will destroy or de-identify that information (provided it is lawful to do so).

* * *

### What kind of personal information does Baby Bunting collect and hold?

Any personal information that you provide via our websites or directly is collected and managed by Baby Bunting.

If you provide your personal information to a third party via a link from the Baby Bunting website, that information is collected and managed by those third parties. Once you have used these links to leave our site, please note that we do not have any control over the third party site. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites, which are not governed by this privacy statement. You should familiarise yourself with their privacy policy prior to deciding whether you wish to provide them with your information.

The types of personal information Baby Bunting may collect includes (but is not limited to) your:

  * name;
  * date of birth;
  * gender;
  * marital status and family details;
  * residential address;
  * email address;
  * contact telephone numbers;
  * identification details;
  * testimonials or opinions;
  * photos of you or your family;
  * financial information including credit card details;
  * written or verbal contact with Baby Bunting, including voice recordings of telephone conversations you have had with our employees; and
  * activities, including but not limited to family, lifestyle and other interests.

If you provide us with information about any third party, you must obtain that person’s permission to give us the information, and inform them that you have given the information to us.

* * *

### How does Baby Bunting use your personal information?

We use your personal information for a variety of reasons including to:

  * provide services and products to you;
  * answer your inquiries and deliver customer service to you;
  * tell you about products or services that we think may be of interest to you;
  * maintain and improve customer services;
  * meet our legal obligations; 
  * consider making offers for employment purposes;
  * manage and resolve any legal or commercial complaints and issues;
  * carry out internal functions including training; and
  * conduct marketing research and analysis.

Whilst you may opt not to provide us with your personal information, you should be aware that without this personal information, we may not be able to provide you with some of the services and/or products you are seeking.

* * *

### In what circumstances will Baby Bunting disclose your personal information?

In the course of conducting our business and providing our products and services to you, we may disclose your personal information. We will often be required to provide your personal details such as your name and address to third party companies who perform part of our service delivery & installation such as fulfillment contractors and mail houses.

We only disclose personal information for the purposes for which it was given to us, or for purposes which are directly related to one of our functions or activities.  We do not give it to anyone else unless one of the following applies:

  * you have consented to the disclosure;
  * you would reasonably expect, or have been told, that your information is passed to those individuals, bodies or agencies; or
  * it is otherwise required or authorised by law.

If we engage third party agents or contractors, we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that they do not breach privacy requirements in relation to the information, before we share your personal information with them.

* * *

### Who do we disclose your personal information to?

We may disclose your personal information to:

  * professional advisers (such as lawyers or auditors);
  * payment systems operators and financial institutions;
  * organisations authorised by Baby Bunting to conduct promotional, research or marketing activities;
  * upon lawful request from law enforcement agencies or government authorities; and
  * any persons acting on your behalf including those persons nominated by you, executors, trustees and legal representatives.

In all circumstances where your personal information is disclosed, we will take all steps reasonable to ensure that these third parties undertake to protect your privacy.

* * *

### Direct marketing

We are committed to compliance with all laws and requirements relating to the use of your personal information.  We will only use or disclose your personal information for direct marketing purposes if you have provided your information for that purpose (and you would expect us to use the information for that purpose), or if you have provided consent for your information to be used in this way.

From time to time, we may contact you with information about products and services offered by us and our related entities and our business partners, which we think may be of interest to you.  When we contact you it may be by mail, telephone, email or SMS.

Where we use or disclose your personal information for the purpose of direct marketing, we will:

  * allow you to request not to receive direct marketing communications (also known as ‘opting-out’); and
  * comply with your request to ‘opt-out’ of receiving further communications within a reasonable timeframe.

If you do not wish to be contacted by Baby Bunting, please contact us via email to [enquiries@babybunting.com.au](mailto:enquiries@babybunting.com.au).

* * *

### Does Baby Bunting disclose your personal information to overseas recipients?

In some circumstances, Baby Bunting may disclose your personal information to overseas recipients. If this occurs, we take steps as are reasonable in the circumstances to ensure that the overseas recipient does not breach the relevant privacy laws in relation to that information.

Sometimes we use third party platforms to deliver information. These are sites hosted and managed by organisations other than ourselves, and some of these sites are hosted overseas. Baby Bunting’s e-mail platform is maintained in the United States. The security details for this platform can be accessed at <http://mailchimp.com/about/security/>.

From time to time we will also run competitions on Facebook. Facebook entry data from competitions are held by Pagemodo [http://www.pagemodo.com](http://www.pagemodo.com/) which is based in the United States.

Your personal information may be stored in a secure and encrypted form overseas (e.g. in data storage and cloud computing facilities operated by us (or by third parties on Baby Bunting’s behalf).

* * *

### Use of Government Identifiers

Baby Bunting will not use Government Identifiers, such as Medicare numbers, or a driver's licence number as its own identifier of individuals.

* * *

### Data quality and Security

We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is stored securely and is protected from misuse and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

The personal information that we collect about you is stored on our database server managed by Baby Bunting Pty Ltd, and its collection, storage, use and disclosure is governed by the terms of the _Privacy Act 1988._

This includes a range of systems and communication security measures, as well as the secure storage of any hard copy documents. In addition, access to your personal information will be restricted to those properly authorised to have access.

We keep your personal information for as long as it is required to provide you with the products you requested from us and to comply with legal requirements. If we no longer require your personal information for any purpose, including legal purposes, we will take reasonable steps to securely destroy or de-identify your personal information.

If you believe that your personal information is not accurate, complete or up to date, please contact us via email to [enquiries@babybunting.com.au](mailto:enquiries@babybunting.com.au).

* * *

### Website usage

Our website is professionally hosted and operates in a secure environment. You should however be aware that there is always an inherent risk in transmitting your personal information via the Internet.

We use Magento Enterprise to process online orders. Customers can see their cards being debited in real time, all in an SSL secure environment.

We take website and credit card security extremely seriously, and always endeavour to provide a secure safe platform on which to conduct online transactions - [babybunting.com.au](http://www.babybunting.com.au/) uses SecurePay and PayPal SSL.

#### PayPal

PayPal automatically encrypts your confidential information in transit from your computer to ours using the Secure Sockets Layer protocol (SSL) with an encryption key length of 128-bits (the highest level commercially available). Before you even register or log in to the PayPal site, our server checks that you're using an approved browser - one that uses SSL 3.0 or higher.

Once your information reaches the PayPal site, it resides on a server that is heavily guarded both physically and electronically. PayPal servers sit behind an electronic firewall and are not directly connected to the internet, so your private information is available only to authorised computers.

#### SecurePay

SecurePay’s security is focused on the safe processing and storage of sensitive personal Credit Card, Charge Card and Direct Entry information.  PCI DSS (Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard) compliance is a strict security standard the card schemes (Visa and MasterCard) have introduced globally to ensure personal information is properly protected. SecurePay holds the highest level of PCIDSS accreditation.  SecurePay's Operations Network is audited on an ongoing basis by external auditors, namely Vectra Corporation, for the purpose of certifying compliance with PCI DSS. Ongoing network scans, a requirement of PCI DSS, are completely regularly and are performed by McAfee Secure.

To make sure you are accessing a secure server, check for the unbroken key or closed lock symbol located generally either at the bottom left or top right of your browser window. If it appears, then SSL is active. You can double check this by looking at the URL as well. If SSL is active, then the first characters of that line will read ‘https’ rather than just ‘http’. It is important for you to take steps to protect against unauthorised access to your password and to your computer.  Also, you should ensure you logout when you have finished visiting [babybunting.com.au](http://www.kathmandu.com.au/), especially if you access it from a shared computer.

Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer for record-keeping purposes. The information collected may be used by Baby Bunting to improve your experience on our website. If you visit an area of the website where you are not required to log on, to read, browse or download information, our system will record the date and time of your visit to our site, the pages viewed and any information downloaded. However, our system will not record any personally identifiable information about you without your consent.

If you complete an online form on our website, the information that you enter on that form will only be collected if you actually submit the form to us. If you change your mind and do not submit the information, any information you have entered up to that point will not be collected by our system and will be discarded (note that if your browser has an “auto complete” function, it might automatically fill in the form again the next time you visit that page).

Any personal information that you actually submit to us using our website or in an e-mail will only be used in accordance with this privacy policy.

Baby Bunting endeavours to ensure the accuracy of our website pricing and content.  In the case of a technical based pricing or content error, we reserve the right to cancel or refund the mistaken purchase price to you.  If an order is rejected on our website we will endeavour to notify you within a reasonable time after the order has been submitted.

If you come across what you believe to be a technical error or inaccuracy of our content please notify us at [enquiries@babybunting.com.au](mailto:enquiries@babybunting.com.au).

* * *

### Links to third party sites

Whilst links to third party websites are provided on our website, we are not responsible for the content or practices of these third party websites.

These links are provided for your convenience and do not represent Baby Bunting's endorsement of any linked third party website. We recommend that you check the privacy policies of these third parties prior to providing them with your personal information.

No links may be made to this website without our prior written consent. Applications for consent must be made to [enquiries@babybunting.com.au](mailto:enquiries@babybunting.com.au).

* * *

### How you can access or correct your personal information

You can request access to the personal information we hold about you at any time, and we will

provide you with that information unless we are prevented by law from giving it to you.

If we are unable to give you access to the information you have requested, we will give you reasons for this decision when we respond to your request.

You will not be charged for accessing your information, although we might have to charge the reasonable cost of processing your request, including photocopying, administration and postage. We will advise you of any fee payable before we process your request.

If you believe that your personal information is not accurate, complete or up to date, please contact us via email to [enquiries@babybunting.com.au](mailto:enquiries@babybunting.com.au). and we will take reasonable steps to correct this information. 

* * *

### How you can notify us of a privacy concern or contact our Privacy Contact Officer

If you:

  * have queries, concerns or complaints about the manner in which your personal information has been collected or handled by Baby Bunting; or
  * would like to request access to or correction of the personal information we hold about you:

**Please Email** :     please contact us via email to [enquiries@babybunting.com.au](mailto:enquiries@babybunting.com.au).

or

** ** **Write to** : Baby Bunting’s Privacy Contact Officer, 955 Taylors Rd, Dandenong South VIC 3175. 

If you consider your privacy concerns have not been resolved satisfactorily by us, or you wish to obtain more information on privacy requirements, you can contact The Office of the Australian Information Commissioner on 1300 363 992 or visit their website at [www.oaic.gov.au](http://www.oaic.gov.au/).

_Last updated 15/04/2014_
